[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
tricentis tasa Advanced
Training as you all know have already
published 59 YouTube videos covering
beginners intermediate and advanced
level
Concepts from couple of videos onwards
have started teaching you the realtime
scenarios where you might encounter with
different types of obstacles and how can
we solve those obstacles while
automating your test cases by using
tricentis tasa this is our obstacle
18 in terms of real time scenarios and
this is our lesson 60 in terms of
overall tricentis TSA training please do
subscribe to the channel click on Bell
icon you'll receive notifications
whenever I publish more videos don't
forget to like and share the video thank
you in this lesson I'm going to teach
you a realtime scenario where you need
to solve an
obstacle by interacting with a web table
which is dynamic in nature the content
of the web table is dynamic and the
number of rows of the web table is
dynamic so you need to
interact with search Dynamic web table
and calculate the number of rows of that
particular web table and enter the
number of rows into a web
application so now let us go to our
obstacle list and understand in detail
what is the obstacle that we need to
solve for so this is our obstacle the
obstacle name is lots of r
and it is categorized as medium so let's
go for
it so here in order to complete this
obstacle you need to count the rows in
the
table input the count into the text
field and click the button labeled click
me you can scroll down here you need to
input the number of rows of this
particular table let us see how many
rows this row how many rows this table
has 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15
16 17 18 so this table has 18 rows if I
enter the rows correctly and then click
me then you solve your automation
problem correctly let me retry again so
now if you see the number of rows
changed this time 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10
11 12 13 right so if I enter it as 12
then what happens we'll see see your
automation problem is not correctly
solved so let me enter 13 and click me
so your automation problem is solved so
that means this table is dynamic in
nature and the content also
changes so how can we solve this let's
go to Tri and tasa as usual we are going
to scan all our objects that are
required for this particular
obstacle under obstacles folder right
click can
application select the application that
you like to scan this is my application
click on
scan we require three objects one is
your web
table your edit box and click me button
let's go back here let's go back to
xcan so here this is my row Count web
table and then this is my edit box where
I'll be entering the row
count and this is my click me
button so these three objects that I
require to automate the scenario now let
us go back to our obstacle and take the
obstacle name copy this
one and name your module with the
obstacle name it is best practice to
name the modules
or name the modules in logical way okay
so done now let's save the
module and close the xcan go back to Tri
sentence so what is the module that we
scanned so this is our this is our new
module that we scanned double click on
this you can see row count table row
count edit box and click me so let us go
back to again
our blue section which is test case
section so let me right click on this
obstacles test case folder and create a
new test case name this with the same
name as your obstacle name and then
double click on this particular obstacle
now let us start automating our test
case for that let me drag this module
and drop onto your test case
so what is our first action we need to
calculate the row count how can we
calculate the row count of your Dynamic
web table so for that what I'm going to
do here I would like to
use a row count property what is the
property I would like to use I would
like to use row count
property your row count is equal to what
I'm doing I'm going to store for the
dynamic row count because see whenever I
execute this particular test case the
row count is not constant it keeps on
changing that's why I would like to
store this row count into a buffer
called
row okay this is my buffer so here if
you want to store the row count into
your buffer you need to select the
action mode as
buffer so what row count I'm storing I'm
storing the row count of this particular
web table so once I store the row count
into a buffer now I need to enter the
row count into the edit box right so
here I would like to call the
buffer where I'm storing the row count
right I would like to call the same
buffer here open curly braces capital B
represents your buffer and then open
Square braces what is the buffer name
Rose is your buffer name close Square
braces and then close your curly
braces so this is my buffer I'm calling
the buffer I'm basically entering the
value stored in a
buffer and then I need to click on this
particular click me button that I'm
going to select click option and your
action mode for these two will be
input right now let's change the work
state as
completed and now let us save the test
case so let me run this particular test
case and see if it works for us okay
right click and run in
scratchbook let us see if it calculates
the row count correctly
see it entered the row count correctly
so let me try again let me execute the
same test one more time so this time
your row count is going to change
earlier it was 18 right so let me WR
retry this one okay let's go back here
and let me run this particular test one
more time right
click and then run in scratchbook
see it entered the Ron correctly and
then clicked
on click me
button so which means our test case
automation is successful so you can see
the test results here okay so here the
row count is stored under buffer which
is 18 and then we are entering the same
18 here okay so if you have any queries
leave your queries in the comment box
hope you all understand how can we
automate the obstacle which involves the
dyamic web
table hope you all understand how can we
solve an obstacle where we need to count
the number of rows in a dynamic web
table and you need to input the count of
number of rows into a text field by
using the concepts called dynamic table
count number of rows by using row count
concept please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos don't forget to like and
share the video thank you
[Music]